那个女孩一定是在对我放电
I'm telling you, that girl totally winked at me!
-她才没有  -她才没有
- She did not wink at you.  - She did not wink at you.
你总觉得有人在对你放电
You always think somebody's winking at you.
我会说是  范莫里森唱的"土菠萝蜜"
I have to say "Tupelo Honey" by Van Morrison.
不会吧
No way!
我认为最浪漫的歌是"往日情怀"
The most romantic song ever was "The Way We Were."
我觉得是艾尔顿·约翰
See, I, I think the one that Elton John
给演《妙管家》的那人写的歌
wrote for that guy on Who's the Boss?
那是什么歌
What song was that?
抱紧我  年轻的托尼·丹泽
Hold me close Young Tony Danza
-莫妮卡 -莫妮卡
-Hi,Monica. -Hi,Mon.
莫妮卡早
Hey, Mon.
天啊
Oh,my God!
-她到底有没有睡觉  -没有
- Has she slept at all? - No.
没有  已经连续三个晚上了
No, it's been three nights in a row.
昨天她终于不哭了
Yeah, she finally stopped crying yesterday.
可后来她又在阳台发现了理查抽过的雪茄
But then she found one of Richard's cigar butts out on the terrace....
好吧  这解释了
Okay,that explains it.
我在凌晨两点接到的那通电话
I got a call at 2 in the morning...
对方只能发出一些咯吱咯吱的声响
...and all I could hear was like this squeaky sound.
我就想一定是老鼠或负鼠打来的
So I thought,"Oh, okay, It's like a mouse or a possum."
接着我才意识到
Then I realized,like...
拜托  老鼠或负鼠
okay, where would a mouse or a possum
怎么会有钱打电话呢
get the money to make the phone call?
-早  -早
-Morning. -Morning.
你做了松饼啊
You made pancakes?
是啊  你还以为我真的会做呢
Yeah, like there's any way I could ever do that.
莫妮卡和瑞秋那儿有糖浆
Monica and Rachel had syrup
我可以让我的男人开心了
Now I can get my man to cheer up
早安  乔伊
Good morning,Joey.
早安
Good morning.
不如这样  我有个主意
Hey, you know what? Here's a thought.
你干脆别去上班  在家陪陪我如何
Why don't you stay home from work and just hang out with me?
我也想啊
Oh,I wish.
你有报告要写  而我得去见律师
You have that report to finish,and I've got to see my lawyer.
我真不敢相信  我竟然跟要离婚的女人约会
I can't believe I'm going out with somebody who's getting divorced.
我真是成年人了
I'm such a grownup.
我要走了  我要走了
I gotta go,I gotta go.
不过你得先吻我一下
Not without a kiss.
或者我就不吻你  这样你就不走了
Maybe I won't kiss you and then you'll have to stay.
亲她  快亲她
Kiss her. Kiss her!
再见甜心  再见乔伊
I'll see you later, sweetie. Bye, Joey.
再见  珍妮斯
Bye-bye,Janice.
你准备什么时候甩了她
So when are you dumping her?
不会
Nope.
这次不会了
Not this time.
拜托  别忽悠我了
Come on,quit yanking me.
我又没有忽悠你
I'm not yanking you.
-她可是珍妮斯  -对  我知道
-This is Janice. -Yeah,I know.
她让我很快乐
She makes me happy.
好吧  好吧
Okay, alright.
你看着我的眼睛  不许眨眼  告诉我
You look me in the eye and tell me,without blinking...
说你不会跟她分手  不许眨眼睛
...that you're not breaking up with her. No blinking.
我不会跟她分手
I'm not breaking up with her!
天啊  你看我在下水道里发现什么
God,look what I found in the drain!
什么
What?
这些是理查的头发
It's some of Richard's hair!
我该怎么处理
What do I do with this?
首先就是把它从我身边拿开
Getting it away from me would be job one.
这确实挺诡异的  但我并不想把它丢掉
It's weird, but you know, I don't want to throw this away.
这些是我仅有的属于他的东西
I mean, this is like all I have left of him.
呕心的
Gross...
下水管的头发
...drain hair.
真好玩  好像有一个小人
Cool! It looks like a tiny little person
在你的麦片里淹死了
drowning in your cereal.
-我是怎么了  -你需要些睡眠
-God, what is wrong with me? -You need to get some sleep.
我需要的是理查
I need to get some Richard.
莫妮卡  你跟他分手是有原因的
Monica, you broke up with him for a reason.
我知道  我只是不想再这么想他
I know. I know. I'm just so tired of missing him.
不愿再去想他为何不打来
I'm tired of wondering why he hasn't called.
他为什么不打来
Why hasn't he called?
可能因为你叫他别再打来了
Maybe because you told him not to?
你是谁啊  记忆女王吗
What are you,the Memory Woman?
他们不会分手了  我是说钱德勒和珍妮斯
They're not breaking up! Chandler and Janice?
他们不会分手了  他都没眨一下眼
They're not breaking up! He didn't blink or anything!
我一点也不惊讶  你看过他们在一起的样子吗
Well you know, I'm not surprised. Did you really see them together?
他们真的好可爱
They're really cute.
可爱  我说的可是珍妮斯
"Cute"? This is Janice!
你还记得珍妮斯吗
You remember Janice?
我记得啊  她是很烦人  但是你知道吗
Yes,Joey, I remember. She's annoying. But you know what?
她现在是他的女朋友  那我们该怎么办
She's his girlfriend now. I mean,what can we do?
这就对了  我要的就是
There you go! That's the spirit
这种不妥协的精神  "我们该怎么办"
I'm looking for! "What can we do?"
好  谁先来  罗斯
All right,who's first,huh? Ross?
我想钱德勒是我们的朋友
Well, I think Chandler's our friend,
而珍妮斯能让他快乐
and Janice makes him happy.
所以我们就成熟点  接受她
So I say we all just be adult about it and accept her.
这个先归在B计划  好吗
Yeah, we'll call that Plan B, alright?
甜心
Honey...
我刚才在想
... I was wondering...
你那套海军制服还在吗
...do you still have that Navy uniform?
不  我还给戏服店了
No,I had to return it to the costume place.
我还有一套高中乐团的旧制服
I think I have an old band uniform from high school.
-你记得高中生不能做爱吧 -是啊
- You remember not having sex in high school,right? - Mm.
-甜心  那么你呢  -什么
- Well,honey,what about you?  -What?
你有过任何有趣的幻想之类的吗?
I mean, fun,you know, fantasy-type things?
没有
No.
别这样  你一定有的
Come on. You gotta have one.
没有
Nope.
-罗斯 你知道吗  -什么
- Ross, you know what? - What?
如果你跟我说  或许我会帮你实现
If you tell me,I might do it.
好吧
Okay.
你有没有看过《星际大战之绝地大反攻》
Did you ever see Return of the Jedi?
看过
Yeah.
你记不记得有一场
Do you remember the scene...
赫特人贾巴的戏
...with Jabba the Hutt?
贾巴把莉亚公主
See, Jabba had as his prisoner...
挟持了
... Princess Leia.
莉亚公主当时穿着
Princess Leia was wearing...
金色的比基尼
...this gold bikini thing.
真好看
It was pretty cool.
莉亚公主穿金色比基尼
Yeah. Princess Leia and the gold bikini?
我们这年纪的男人都很喜欢
Every guy our age loved that.
真的吗
Really?
那是意义重大的一刻
It's huge!
那一刻她不再是个公主
That's the moment when you know, she stopped being a princess...
而变成了  一个普通的女人
...and she became,like,you know,a woman, you know.
你扮过莉亚公主吗
Did you ever do the Leia thing?
真的吗  有那么刺激吗
Really? That great,huh?
不  是我买了新的寻呼机  调成振动了
No,it's just that I got this new pager,and I have it on "vibrate."
再见
See you.
-嗨  -你们好啊
- Hey! - Hi,you guys!
你看我在四川龙餐厅外找到谁了
Look who I found standing outside the Szechuan Dragon...
一直盯着停车收费表不放
...staring at a parking meter.
小莫  你好啊
Mon. Hi.
-你怎么没去上班  -他们把我送回家了
-Why aren't you at work? -Oh,they sent me home.
为什么
Why?
-因为我并不在四川龙餐厅上班  -天啊
- Because I don't work at the Szechuan Dragon. -Oh, god.
你真的需要好好休息
You really, really need to get some sleep.
我知道该睡了
I know I do.
-你猜怎么着  -什么
- Guess what?   - What?
他们要出版我的文章
They published my paper.
-真的吗  -是啊
- Really? -Yes.
瑞秋  你看
Rach, look!
我那强壮的罗斯天行者何时会来拯救我
Where is my strong Ross Skywalker to come rescue me?
他来了
There he is!
-幸运  -之
- Wheel! - Of!
轮
Fortune!
这个家伙真蠢
This guy's so stupid.
是拉什莫尔公爵啦
It's Count Rushmore!
你真的该去参加这个节目
You know, you should really go on this show.
我有三张今晚流浪者比赛的票 你意下如何
Alright, listen. I got three tickets to the Rangers tonight. What do you say?
我去定了
I say I am there!
太棒了
Cool!
罗斯也会去吗
Is Ross going too?
不  珍妮斯去
No. Janice.
珍妮斯
Janice?
我只是替罗斯难过  你知道吗
Because I just feel bad for Ross,you know?
我们总是一起去的
I mean, we always go together.
我们就像曲棍球三兄弟
We're like The Three Hockey-teers,you know?
我可能误会你了
You know, I may be way out on a limb here,
但还是问一句  你是不是对珍妮斯不满
but do you, do you have a problem with Janice?
没有
No!
是啦
Yes....
天啊  我该怎么说
Oh, God, how do I say this?
你知道希腊餐厅里那个头发很蓬的女孩子
You know that girl from the greek restaurant with the hair?
那个我讨厌的女孩子  她快把我逼疯了
That girl that I hate? She drives me crazy.
我并不讨厌珍妮斯  只是她不那么好相处
Look,I don't hate Janice. She's just a lot to take, you know?
你总算说出来了
Well,there you go.
拜托  别那样看着我
Come on, man. Don't look at me like that.
以前她也快把你逼疯  还记得吗
She used to drive you nuts before too,remember?
但是我现在为她疯狂  这次可能是真爱
Yeah, I'm crazy about her now. I think this could be the real thing.
大写的真  大写的爱
Capital R,capital T!
别担心  字母没拼错
Don't worry,those are the right letters.
你到底要我说什么
Look, what do you want me to say?
-我要你说你喜欢她  -我办不到
- I want you to say that you like her! - I can't
这就像是某种化学反应
lt's like this chemical thing, you know?
每次她一开口笑  我就想...
Every time she starts laughing,I just wanna...
就想把我的手臂拧下来  好往她身上扔
...pull my arm off just so I have something to throw at her.
谢谢你的努力
Thanks for trying.
对了  根本就没有拉什莫尔公爵
Oh,and by the way,there is no Count Rushmore!
那是谁在拉什莫尔山上雕了那些总统肖像
Then who's the guy that painted the faces on the mountain?
你怎么可以告诉她
How could you have told her?
罗斯  我是想又没什么大不了的
Ross, I didn't think it would be that big a deal!
她认为没什么大不了的
She didn't think it would be that big a deal!
你想讨论这些的时候  你都会跟谁说
Okay, who are you talking to when you do that?
这些应该是仅限于我们之间的私密对话
Look,that was supposed to be a private,personal thing between us.
菲比是我的闺蜜  好吗 我们无话不谈
Okay, Ross, Phoebe is my girlfriend,okay? We tell each other everything.
拜托  男人也一样啊
I mean, come on. You guys do the same thing.
那些更衣室里的对话怎么说
I mean,what about all that locker-room stuff?
那不一样
That's different. Okay?
我们会聊  比如谁跟脱衣舞娘约会了
That's like, who dated a stripper?
或谁在史坦登岛渡轮后面做爱
Or who did it on the back of the Staten lsland ferry?
-都是乔伊干的吧  -没错
- Both of those Joey? - Yeah.
但是绝不会谈到自己的女朋友
But you don't, you don't talk about like, you know, your girlfriend...
还有和她之间亲密的事
...and the intimate stuff you do with her.
连最好的朋友也不说吗
Not even with your best friend?
不说
No.
真可悲
That is so sad.
你们错过太多乐趣了  罗斯
You're missing out on so much, Ross.
那是种彼此维系  分享的乐趣
I mean,the bonding and the sharing, you know...
得知别人也有过和你一样的遭遇
...and knowing that someone else is going through the same thing you are.
那你们什么都跟对方说吗
So, what, you tell each other everything?
差不多
Pretty much.
你有没有说过—夜五次的纪录
Did you talk about the Night of Five Times?
你有没有告诉她们  那一夜五次的纪录
Do you tell people about the Night of Five Times?
甜心  你那次是跟凯萝
Honey,that was with Carol.
我知道  我想还是值得一提
I know,but it's still worth mentioning,I think.
全身肌肉放松
Relax every muscle in your body.
听着叮叮咚咚的音乐
Listen to the plinky-plunky music.
好  闭上你的眼睛
Okay,now close your eyes...
去想一个令人愉快的地方
...and think of a happy place.
告诉我  能让你快乐的地方在哪
Tell me your happy place.
理查家的客厅  一起喝酒
Richard's living room,drinking wine.
不  不可以跟理查有关
No,no,no. Not a Richard thing.
把酒杯放下快出来
Just put down the glass and get out.
对不起  但那是让我快乐的地方
I'm sorry,but that's my happy place.
好  我的快乐之所借你用吧
Okay,fine. Use my happy place.
但我得请你别把那儿弄乱
Just I'm gonna have to ask you, don't move anything in there.
我会尽量的
I'll try not to.
好，你现在在一片草地上
All right,so,you're in a meadow...
天上有一片繁星
... millions of stars in the sky
你觉得分手是错误的吗
You think breaking up was a huge mistake?
快乐之所  禁问问题
Okay, there are no questions in the happy place.
只有和煦的微风  和从树上撒下的月光
Okay, just the warm breeze and the moonlight flowing through the trees.
我赌他一定忘了我  我打赌他好得很
I'll bet he's totally over me. I'll bet he's fine.
快乐之所  禁止赌博和下注
Betting and wagering of any kind, I'm sure, are not permitted in the happy place.Okay?
那里只有  美丽的瀑布
There's just,you know,the lovely waterfalls...
和缓缓喷薄的喷泉
...and the trickling fountains...
流淌的小溪  奏出宁静的音律
...and the calming sounds of the babbling brook.
好了  一点用也没有
Okay, this isn't working.
我还是醒着的  而且我要尿尿
I'm still awake,and now I have to pee.
我听说
So I hear...
你讨厌我
...you hate me!
我没说过讨厌这个词  我用词可是很小心的
I never said hate. I was very careful about that.
有人私下告诉我
A little birdie told me something about
你想拧下手臂扔到我身上
you wanted to rip your arm off and throw it at me.
这样你就觉得我讨厌你
And you got "hate" from that?
你也太断章取义了吧
You're taking a big leap there.
好吧  好吧  好吧
All right,fine,fine,fine!
我们得想点法子解决我们的小摩擦
We have got to do something about our little situation here, Joey.
我是这么想的
So this is my idea.
你和我花点时间好好相处
You and me spending some quality time together.
但是这有什么...
But what does that...
为了钱德勒
For Chandler!
好吧  我答应
Okay. I'm in.
好  今天就叫做
Okay! Alright, this is what we'll call it:
"乔伊和珍妮斯的逍遥一日游"
Joey and Janice's Day of Fun!
要一整天啊
Does it have to be a whole day?
对  因为要爱上我得要一整天那么长
Yes,because that's how long it takes to love me.
我知道  我就睡在你们的隔壁
Yeah,I know. I sleep in the next room.
我今天去了邮局
So I went down to the post office...
寄来的是我订的录影带
...and it turns out it was those videos that I ordered...
是帮理查订的  有关内战的
...for Richard about the Civil War.
他很喜欢看内战片
He loved the Civil War.
莫妮卡  你要不要我们带你回家
Monica, do you want us to take you home?
带我到遥远的银河去吧
Or maybe to a galaxy far,far away.
女人之间什么话都说
Women tell each other everything!
-这你知道吗  -知道啊
- Did you know that?  -Hmm, yeah.
不  钱德勒  我是说所有的事
No, Chandler, everything.
你的偏好  她的偏好
Like stuff you like. Stuff she likes.
技巧  持久力  腰围
Technique. Stamina. Girth.
还有腰围
Girth?
为什么  为什么会这样
Why? Why? Why?
这有什么好说的
Why would they do this?
瑞秋说分享的感觉很棒  而且以为
Rachel says sharing's great and supposedly...
我们也会这么做
...we ought to be doing it.
你想说吗
Do you want to?
-我们不会要讨论腰围吧  -不用
- We're not gonna talk about girth, are we? - No.
好  你先吧
All right,you go first.
好  我先说
Okay. Okay,I'll go first.
有天晚上
So the other night...
瑞秋和我在床上  讨论性幻想
...Rachel and I are in bed talking about fantasies...
我就描述了《星际大战》里的
...and I happened to describe a particular...
某个场景
... Star Wars thing
-莉亚公主和金色比基尼  -没错
- Princess Leia and the gold bikini. - Yes!
-我知道  -没错
- I know! - Yes!
说出来倒挺容易的
Well, well, that, that was easy.
好  换你了
Okay,you go.
-好的  -说吧
-Okay. -Okay.
当你跟一个女人在床上
Okay,you know when you're in bed with a woman...
亲昵的时候
and... you know, you fooling around with her...
脑袋里突然出现一些疯狂的画面
...and you get all these mental images in your brain?
比如超级名模艾拉·麦克弗森
Like Elle MacPherson
或是影印店的那个女孩
or that girl at the Xerox place?
-穿了肚脐环的那个 -我知道
- With the belly button ring? -I know.
但是突然之间  你妈忽然跃入脑海
And then all of a sudden,your mom pops into your head.
于是你就想  "妈  快走开"
And you're,like,"Mom,get out of here!"
但这之后  你就完全没情绪了
But of course, after that, you can't possibly think of anything else.
而你正在做的事又不能停止
And you can't, you know, stop what you're doing.
所以你就只能...
So it's kind of like you're...
你懂的
...you know...
...you know....
你不懂啊
You don't know!
你妈
Your mom?
你竟然会想到你妈  你有什么毛病啊
You're telling me about your mom? What's the matter with you?
-是你说...  -我说要分享  不是吓唬人
-You said -I said "share," not "scare"!
你给我坐到那边去
Go sit over there!
我们回来了
We're back!
你们俩在一起干嘛
What are you guys doing together?
乔伊和珍妮斯的逍遥一日游
Joey and Janice's Day of Fun!
真的吗
Really?
我们去看纽约大都会的比赛  还吃了中国菜
Yeah, yeah, we went to a Mets game. We got Chinese food.
我爱上这个女人了
And, you know, I love this woman.
你有竞争对手了  兄弟
You have got competition, buddy.
我只是上来亲你一下
Well, I just came by to give you a kiss.
我得去接孩子了  待会儿见  甜心
I have to go pick up the baby. So, I'll see you later, sweetheart.
你也是  钱德勒
You too, Chandler.
你还是受不了她  是吗
You still can't stand her,can you?
抱歉  我已尽最大努力了
I'm sorry,man, I tried! I really did!
谢谢你的努力
You know, I appreciate you giving it a shot.
但是往好处想
But hey, look, you know,the good thing is...
我们一起过了一整天  我竟然还活着
...is that we spent the whole day together and I survived.
更了不起的是  她也还活着
And what's even more amazing, so did she.
今天是大都会主场的球棒日
It was Bat Day at Shea Stadium.
我想值得一去
I guess that's something.
天啊  这可是件盛事
Oh,man, that's huge!
现在我确定我可以忍受和她待在一起
Now I know I can stand to be around her.
也就是说
Which means...
我可以和你们一起出去了
... I get to hang out with you.
这才是我的重点
Which is kind of the whole point anyway.
好吧
Okay.
我们刚刚去了咖啡店  遇到了罗斯
Oh, hey! Chandler, we stopped by the coffee shop and ran into Ross.
天啊
Oh, God.
希望这么说会让你好过点
If it makes you feel any better,
我也有过这种想法
I do it too.
-真的吗  -对啊
- Really? - Oh,yeah!
我在做爱时  常常会想像你妈的样子
I always picture your mom when I'm having sex.
1861年4月12日
April 12,1861.
美国驻守在萨姆特堡的部队受到炮轰
The United States garrison at Fort Sumter was fired upon.
这场炮轰是由于...
It is now under bombardment by...
爸  你怎么来了
Hey, Dad! What are you doing?
你妈今晚打桥牌  所以我进城来抱抱莫妮卡
It's your mother's bridge night,so l came into the city for a little Moni-cuddle.
你什么时候开始抽雪茄了
Since when did you start smoking cigars?
我没有  只是喜欢闻它的味道
I don't. I just like the smell of them.
你来这里真正的目的是什么
So what are you really doing here, dad?
我只想确定一下你还好吧
I just wanted to make sure you're okay.
我为什么会不好
What makes you think that Why I might not be okay?
我看到理查了
I saw Richard.
你还好吗
So how do you doing?
我很好
I'm fine.
我只是有点累  不过还好
I'm just a little tired,but I'm okay.
-理查怎么样了  -你不会想知道的
-How's Richard doing? -You don't want to know.
我真的很想知道
No, I really, really do.
他的情况很糟
Well,he's doing terrible!
真的
Really?
比他跟芭芭拉分手时还糟
Worse than when he broke up with Barbara.
你不是故意这么说的吧
You're not just saying that,are you?
那个男人简直一团糟
No,the man is a mess!
他有没有哭
- Was he crying? - No.
你觉得他会不会是要等你走后再哭
Do you think he was waiting till after you left,so he could cry?
或许吧
Maybe.
我想也是
I think so.
宝贝  感情这回事很难说  就像我跟你妈
Honey,relationships are hard. Like with your mom and me.
大学毕业后  我们曾分手过一阵子
You know,after we graduated from college,we broke up for a while.
她父亲  就是你祖父  似乎
It seems her father,your grandfather...
希望你妈跟他一样  到欧洲四处旅行
...wanted her to travel around Europe like he did.
当然  他去欧洲是看在钱的份上
Of course,he got to do it on Uncle Sam's nickel...
因为当时他也在猛轰德国军用列车
... because he was also strafing German troop trains at the time.
然而
However....
好吧  开始了
Okay,here we go.
我是贾巴的囚犯  而你...
I am Jabba's prisoner. And you...
你脸上的表情好诡异
... have a really weird look on your face.
怎么了  甜心  有什么问题
What? Honey,what is it?
我的发型不对吗
Did I get wrong, did I get the hair wrong?
还是别的问题
Or what?
跟你想像得不同  怎么回事
Did you just picture it differently? What, what?
不不  不是你的问题  是...
No, no. It's not you. It's, it's....
怎么了  拜托  甜心  你把我吓坏了
What is it? Come on, sweetie. You're,like,freaking me out here.
我恨钱德勒  那个混蛋毁了我的人生
I hate Chandler. The bastard ruined my life!